mixtelematics.com 2019-05-28

# MiX Telematics Privacy Notice | Data Security

This Privacy Notice is effective as of May 2018. You find the previous version here.  

This Privacy Notice sets out how MiX Telematics International (Pty) Ltd (“MiX Telematics”) uses and protects any data that you give MiX Telematics when you use this website and affiliated digital MiX Telematics property that links to this Privacy Notice. This notice discloses what type of personal data about our websites’ users is gathered and tracked, to how the data is used, shared or otherwise processed offline. It also describes how cookies may be used.

## What we collect

When you register on the MiX Telematics website certain data will be collected about you in order to provide you with the services you have requested. We may collect the following personal data: 

    name and job title 

    company name 

    contact data including email address 

    demographic data such as postcode, preferences and commercial interests 

    other data relevant to customer surveys and/or offers.

## What we do with the data we gather

Once you choose to register with MiX Telematics and provide us with personal data, it may be used for the purposes of providing you with the requested information and service. We will not sell, rent or lease your personal data to third parties. 

We require this data to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons: 

    Internal record keeping 

    We may use the data to improve our products and services 

    We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided 

    We may contact you telephonically about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the phone number which you have provided.   

From time to time, we may also use your data to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the data to customise the website according to your interests. 

MiX Telematics may partner with other organisations who may provide you with the services requested through the MiX Telematics website. These partner organisation are required to keep confidential the data received on behalf of MiX Telematics and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for MiX Telematics. MiX Telematics will not share personal data with any other third parties without your permission, unless required by law enforcement action, subpoena, or local law.

## Marketing

The data you provide may be used by MiX Telematics for marketing purposes. Before we do so, we will offer you the opportunity to choose whether or not to have your data used in this way. You may at any time choose not to receive marketing materials from us by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each e-mail you may receive or by indicating so when we call you.

## How long is the data stored?

Your personal data is stored as long as you engage with MiX Telematics on a regular basis. Personal data collected via our websites and digital properties as described in this Privacy Notice will be deleted after one year from the point in time that you have not been active on any of MiX Telematics’ digital platforms and/or not engaged with MiX Telematics. 

Your data may be deleted on request by completing a data deletion request form, and neither you nor or anyone else will be able to access your data after that. 

## Sharing of Personal Data and International Transfers

MiX Telematics is a global organisation with business processes, management structures and technical systems that cross borders. We may share data about you within MiX Telematics and transfer it to countries in the world where we do business in connection with the uses identified above and in accordance with this Privacy Notice. Our Privacy Notice and our practices are designed to provide a globally consistent level of protection for personal data all over the world. This means that even in countries whose laws provide for less protection for your data, MiX Telematics will still handle your data in the manner described here. 

In some cases, MiX Telematics uses suppliers located in various countries to collect, use, analyse, and otherwise process data on its behalf. It is MiX Telematics' practice to require such suppliers to handle data in a manner consistent with the MiX Telematics policies.

## How is the data kept secure and where is it kept? 

MiX Telematics’ web server that serves the websites is located in Germany, hosted in secure data centre. The collected data may be stored in third-party Customer Relationship Management (CRM) systems. MiX Telematics has put in place contractual agreements that safeguard your privacy and data protection rights with these CRM service providers. 

It may be necessary to move or transfer your data into or out of the European Economic Area (EEA) to provide the services described above. 

We conduct regular security and compliance audits in order to keep your data secure.

## How can you request a record of all your personal data that has been collected? 

You may request a record of all of the personal data relating to you that has been collected in accordance with this privacy notice. To do so, please complete this [form](http://www.mixtelematics.com/data-security/information-request).

## How can you withdraw your consent for MiX Telematics to use your data? 

If you have previously consented to allow MiX Telematics to use your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Notice, and you wish to withdraw your consent, you can do so with this [form](http://www.mixtelematics.com/data-security/information-request). 

## How can you request that your personal data is rectified or erased? 

You may request the correction or deletion of your profile data by using this [form](http://www.mixtelematics.com/data-security/information-request).

## How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. 

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. 

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. 

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. 

For more information on cookies, please see: [www.allaboutcookies.org ](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any data which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy notice. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy notice applicable to the website in question.

## Changes to this statement

Please note that these guidelines are subject to change at any time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. You are encouraged to review this Privacy Notice at the inception of each session.

## Acceptance of policy

By using this website, or otherwise providing your personal data to MiX Telematics, you signify your acceptance of our Privacy Notice. If you do not agree to this notice, please do not use the MiX Telematics website or provide any personal data to MiX Telematics.

## Contacting Us

If you have questions or complaints regarding our Privacy Notice, please contact the [MiX Telematics Data Protection Officer](mailto:gdpr_admin@mixtelematics.com), telephone +27 (11) 654 8225 or the MiX Telematics [Digital Marketing Manager.](http://explore.mixtelematics.com/l/69882/2018-06-08/9pcdlh)

Alternatively, you can write to MiX Telematics (International), PO Box 12377, Die Boord, 7613, South Africa. Our physical address is Blaauwklip Office Park 2, Corner of Strand Street and Weber’s Valley Roads, Stellenbosch, 7600, South Africa.
